hello my name is green and welcome back
to the g team base on hermitcraft you
might be able to see a little room
behind me and i'm going to explain
exactly what this is in just a second
basically me and the team have been
decking out this entire place including
mumbo now who's actually pulling his way
we've been decking this out with traps
tricks and protecting our flags our main
priority at the moment is to create our
flag rooms at the moment our flags are
safely hidden in the ender chest where
they can't be got and that's not because
we're just hiding them there that's
because we literally have nowhere to put
them yet it's only fair that we give
each other enough time to protect our
flags and in our case we're not just
going to trap them but we're going to
challenge team star so iskall has taken
on one flag i have taken on one flag and
stress monster has taken on one flag
each of us is going to be making a
challenge for team star and then there's
going to be some general traps around
the base you'll even see these random
doors
and that was mumbo's doing he's been up
to something but he hasn't told any of
us what he's been doing so there's a
very high possibility that we're going
to die to one of our own traps
anyway this is what i've been working on
now i've done all of this work off
camera i haven't recorded a single
second of this
pretty much because i was just making
the rooms i haven't done anything
spectacular but i have built this room
here which is a large one now this is
going to be a parkour room and then it's
going to move on to this room here which
is going to be a challenge room and then
finally that's where i'm going to keep
the flag in an infinity room for a
special effect
so producing my flag protection room is
my main priority for today's video and i
think i've just about got everything i
need you'll notice there's a lot of lava
involved in this so it's going to be a
lot of fun to make this
but also a lot of work so the first
challenge like i said is going to be a
parkour challenge and i did this because
i don't know how good everyone is at
parkour but it's sometimes pretty
frustrating now i'm not going to make it
impossible all i'm going to do is make
it annoying
i'm actually going to design this so
that only one person should do it i
could even create two paths so i think
i've just done this correctly i haven't
added any redstone yet but this should
be possible as it stands
oh oh no it's not good with the elytra
it's not good with electro we have to
remember that they won't have elytra on
now to mess up
if two people try and do this at once
i'm gonna create a t flippy floppy to
create a bit of disruption now if they
try and like speed run it then they're
gonna have a hard time if they take it
nice and slow they should get through
this and for this side i'm going to
create i think a delayed trap
so this one you've got to stand on but
this one you've got to jump over really
quickly so it's very simple as soon as
you go on this it should
trigger that piston in there but i just
have to make sure i delay it enough so
that they actually have time to jump off
it so if they jump and stay on
they're gonna get pushed off
so let's try this from the start now
i've got that one to work but the delay
might be a bit too long so if i jump
jump i've got to stay here
cool
and then i go over and then i do this
and if i just stay on here too long it
should push push me off perfect
now this isn't even a trap this i really
hope that they just walk over this
because it's not going to blow up it's
not anything
spectacular it's literally just a little
bit of a jingle to make this a little
bit more immersive as a little game
and i just need to look up the note
configuration because i am rubbish at
music but i wonder how many of you know
what this is going to be
hey it works
of course i'd get a random minecraft
cave sound while i was doing that
if it wasn't for the lag because there's
so many people on right now it would
have been perfect
so anyway let's move on to the next room
now this one is going to be a maze but
not just any maze this is actually going
to be timed you're going to have to run
through this and all of its obstacles
while lava is pouring down so the first
thing i need to do
is lay out the pathway so i think i'm
going to keep it one block just one
block to make it really tough
i think i should also create multiple
pathways as well ones that go back on
themselves or something like that just
so it's even more panicky
i can't control how fast the lava will
come down so i'm gonna have to make sure
that this is absolutely possible first
this maze is probably
the most
horrible thing that i've ever created in
this game like seriously there's so many
false turns and this isn't even the
start so immediately you're given a
choice you go down here you look left
you'll see this now remember any block
here that you see there will be lava
from the ceiling so not only do you have
to be fast you have to be perfect in
getting those turns right or you're
gonna end up in lava taking damage and
you're gonna end up on fire and you've
got to make the right turn every single
time or you end up in the lava and when
you start the system it's going to start
dispensing lava above your head so you
have to try and outrun the lava as it's
dispensed behind you and if you mess up
you've got to double back and oh it's
going to be so stressful i'm not sure
that i've made this tall enough to be
honest with you maybe we should get a
bucket of lava and see how quickly this
dispenses
so let's assume for a second that i've
hit the pressure plate and it's going to
come down
i mean the server is quite laggy at the
moment so i'm able to get past fairly
easily yeah it's pretty lag dependent
actually now that i think about it it
does come down quite slowly so if i
if i manage to
time all of the dispensers up there
correctly this could be a decent height
but one false turn could be the end
depends how quick you are how accurate
you are on this
but it should work out quite well
and if anything it's much easier just to
dig this down one block than to move all
the redstone up so i think we'll start
with what we've got here
and there if i put the dispensers like
this they should know what's coming i
mean it's fairly obvious
but this should work i'm really i'm
proud of this idea i don't know if i've
ever seen this done before i mean it
probably has been done it's a
huge amount of work and i'm sort of i'm
i'm sort of like making the maze first
and then worrying about all the redstone
that i've got to make a bit later on if
i max these all out to four or five
ticks i don't know how many there are
this should in theory work
i would have never actually dreamt that
this would work i thought i was gonna
have to you know plug these into the
side of them but hopefully if i can get
away with this it will look absolutely
brilliant
so i've put some white concrete in some
of these let's see
ah
beautiful
so that would continue all the way down
and depending on how much lag there is
the lava will fall down so i'm gonna get
all of these dispensers made and then
pile them full of lava and then we'll
take it from there i think
it's literally the next day because i
had to spend the entire evening putting
the rest of this together and it's just
about ready so this is now the park
orbit i've added in the lava which
should freak anybody out it's not a
particularly difficult parkour it's just
very scary
so i've got a checkpoint here with a bed
to allow them to quickly respawn because
it would suck so much if they you know
they repeatedly died so just giving them
a fair chance and i've made myself a
little cheaty way through because we're
actually going to get stressed to stress
test this whole thing
and make sure that it works the last
thing i need to do is the very last room
i finished with my little jingle
so they get a little reward they'll
probably think that this is a trap but
i'm hoping they'll just run over it
right so now the maze is done now i had
to change my plans quite dramatically
big big shout out to cub fan because i
was struggling infinitely like it might
just none of my redstone it worked my oh
skelebone
so my redstone did work the problem was
it only worked once
so cub fan very kindly came and helped
me out for hours we were up most of the
night
yeah and it's done so big shout out to
cub fan for making this all work so if
you haven't figured it out this is a
maze
and it activates from a pressure plate
as well and you've got to run through
the maze while these dispense lava one
after the other so it is a freaky maze
like it's going to be a power i've lost
my way
uh no okay yeah i see i know the way
quite well now and then you end up in
this room and there's actually water
here just in case you're on fire
i just now need to place all of the item
frames and i've borrowed all of the maps
from my infinity room this room is
actually the worst part of the entire
thing
because
oh oh man because basically they're
gonna run in here and it's likely that
they're just gonna run straight through
and i'm gonna hide
lava
just down here
oh
it's evil i tell you evil i knew i could
use this infinity room concept again and
thankfully i've already got all of those
maps my infinity room back in my base is
a total mess however it's going to be
worth it just for this one joke
this actually may make them rage quit i
i think act they may give up on the flag
altogether
that didn't sound very that didn't sound
good um what's going on
i hope that's nothing to do with me
while we've been making these flag
defense rooms that's very common you
sometimes hear creepers explode you
sometimes hear zombies
the works
so the key here is to because you can't
place item frames on these you open them
up and then you can place item frames on
them for some reason i don't have enough
maps to finish the whole thing but i
have got enough maps to finish the floor
and in theory yep if you crouch you will
make it round i really wish i had enough
maps to finish it but that that will do
for now i'll just explain to stress that
that's it oh man that's that's a really
cool effect okay
we are ready to test this thing okay
guinea pig are you ready to
try and retrieve the flag this is my
flag room welcome to my three-part flag
room of death
okay looks lovely um you are my average
minecraft player that is going to be i
didn't mean that in a bad way i'm so
sorry i meant like i meant
very
my very a very talented guinea pig yes
you're gonna you might want to sleep
though you might want to sleep in this
bed just think just in case you know
nothing about this i haven't shown you a
thing
you've not shown me anything the only
thing that i've seen is this parkour
which i am horrendous at well good luck
i'm gonna watch this unfold from
yourself here place to watch me this is
this is research this is quality
assurance okay when you're ready try and
complete the parkour
i'm gonna miss this first one no you're
not no you're not either actually
horrendous oh okay you made it brilliant
okay
and
oh
you did it you did it all right hang on
that blog's gonna go right no no it's
not it's not i shouldn't tell you that
but it's not oh okay okay
i don't like this
you've done the hard bit now
just well actually that's probably the
hardest that's gonna say don't don't say
that and then kind of like jinx it for
me now
you did it you did it don't jump twice
don't jump twice
i've got the shakes oh my god okay right
let's run again
how do i run again you press ctrl
[Music]
you nailed the control bit but you
forgot the space bar
oh no now this is where oh
okay i did it
oh my god
and again
give me my purpose
okay you know what you you go in the you
go in the glass room
here you take all this stuff here you be
me that took a lot longer than i thought
okay you go in the glass you go in the
glass box go in there don't forget to
seal it up behind you
don't forget
um there we go all right all right
[Laughter]
now you try it now you be i'll be you
oh god here we go
that was a lot better than i did it i
have to say that was a one job hold on i
need to get there we go activate that
again
up huh
oh my god you made me look so bad then
could you not just fall in the lava
oh no oh no
look at me i'm stressed
yeah there we go that's much better now
i feel better about myself
okay so
i think we've established that this
parkour is definitely uh skill based so
it depends how good they are at parkour
but you might you might notice that on
that jump there was a little there was
like a punch that came out of it i don't
know i'm just gonna get you get you go
back i'm gonna all right i'm just gonna
do it again oh they should look weird
where are you there we go
this is like you flying around
everywhere all the time
that's so embarrassing okay all right
moving on
all right now let's uh let's swap again
stop again you gotta give me all the
stuff right now
brilliant there you go okay well done
stress you've done it and as a reward
you get to stand on this pressure plate
oh no come on
yay
now if they're really failing and it
took them a long time to do it there's
another checkpoint here in the bed but
you don't have to have to deal with that
okay so just run through the wall yep
right i'm not going to tell you what
this is
you can have a guess what it is before
you go in but uh
on you go no oh god is it a maze
oh no okay stick to that
oh my god i'm sticking to the right
that's the wrong way
i see nothing
okay so that's pretty much what i would
expect from a first run not knowing what
it is finding out that you're gonna die
from the lava oh no i'm here
oh look you can give it another go
no go on
ah look at that you forgot oh you forgot
the thing just like i intended
[Laughter]
i have the shakes
oh you were so close oh
look at that you were so close yeah i
think i think this is definitely go oh
she's off good luck yeah i'm off
um this way this way this way oh this
way
congratulations
okay and now you can go and get the flag
well hypothetically
oh straight through here oh
oh my god that is
[Laughter]
okay oh that is exactly what i'm hoping
for
oh man that i have to admit that was a
good one you were not you did not see
that coming at all
good job i'm very very impressed you've
done a good job there it's taken so long
okay well test complete and now i can
just put the final touches on this and
it is then totally complete now that it
has been stress tested i have fixed the
exit on the way out and there's
literally one more thing to do i really
should have
covered like uncovered this before i did
this but this is what it looks like with
the infinity room i ran out of maps oh
man this is really gonna be horrible for
whoever does this all right then the
last few maps go in
and oh man i well i don't
i don't like this i don't like this one
bit because i know that there's lava
there and hold on
listen
you can't even hear the lava either for
some reason you can't hear it maybe
because there's a block between us and
the lava no that wouldn't make any sense
i can't hear it
no well maybe it doesn't make a noise
but
oh boy
this this is actually scary i don't know
where i am i think the lava is about
there and there
if i keep going forward crouching i stop
here so the lava is directly below me
oh man
i hope that this works
but for now we're going to completely
leave it i've added this pressure plate
so that when the lava comes down it
doesn't flow in like i just experienced
and then there's a exit there so the
last thing to do is a couple of signs
now because i'm paranoid i'm going to
run through this all myself
once over just to make sure that it
works
shouldn't be too difficult and i've also
added a bunch of signs so let's go and
get rid of all my stuff and then we will
go through this
okay completely without any items except
a couple of potatoes welcome team star
you have chosen to take on green's flag
defense system you have to complete two
challenges to get to the flag it's all
quite self-explanatory good luck
well you're right try not to lose all 15
lives in one go you may want to sleep
and you may want to sleep the night in
case you don't make it oh well there we
go that's that's fortunate it's actually
night time out there all right
limber up limber up
squat squat all right let's go no time
to wait
i obviously know all the ins and outs so
i should be uh nailed that one first
time
and i'm just gonna speedrun this
i know i also know the way through the
maze as well oh do i no i don't oh no
oh one wrong turn can be the end
[Music]
it also depends on how laggy the server
is oh no no
no no no no no no
i was so close
i yeah okay
uh let's pretend that didn't happen and
try again
let's pretend that this didn't happen
either
no maybe this is harder than i thought
oh i cheated the system
okay check point two well done i'm
passing my parkour if only the next
challenge was as skill based as that one
right i've gotta wait for this lava to
drain out and there's also a nice
checkpoint here so if they find this
particularly difficult maybe they lose a
couple of lives they're more than
welcome to then wait the night and then
sleep in here as well just in case
let's go for it
okay okay uh
then i go wait what i've
i could have sworn i knew this
all of this
no i definitely know this
no i definitely don't know this oh no no
again not again
okay it's totally possible even if you
make wrong turns absolutely brilliant
congratulations you have finished my
challenges the flag is inside
oh brilliant
[Laughter]
perfect
absolutely perfect so all i've got to do
now is go and reset that
and we should be good there we go
perfect so that lava is now completely
drained out
that is reset and we are ready to go now
this whole build as you can imagine
thousands of blocks of white concrete as
usual
hundreds of sea lanterns and of course
mining all of this out took a seriously
long time normally i like to do three or
four things per episode but this has
taken me three days and i i do mean that
quite literally three days for this
whole thing to work out
oh my goodness
well at least it's all done now
but i'm afraid that's literally all i
have time for so i'm now ready and
prepared for when they try and get my
flag and i think it's gone stress are
almost finished as well so
i think next episode we might be able to
try and go in the little skirmish and
try and grab one of their flags and
hopefully
we'll get some kills when they try and
get these ones
thank you very much for watching
everyone i hope you've enjoyed this uh
bit off offgreen theme video
good bye